{"tossups": [{"question": "In preparation for this event, the Octagon House was converted into a French consulate for its protection; it was later converted into federal housing. This event, a response to the destruction of private homes during the Raid on Port Dover, was preceded by the Battle of Bladensburg and ended in part by a fluke tornado. This event caused an evacuation of a copy of the Lansdowne Portrait, which was legendarily saved by Dolley Madison. For ten points, name this 1814 event in which British forces torched the capital of the United States.", "answer": "<b> burn</b>ing of<b> Washington</b> D.C. (accept equivalents; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cfire\u201d and\u201cattack on Washington\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Five deities were born from this goddess\u2019s necklace of 500 jewels. To lure this deity out of hiding, a dawn goddess performed a strip tease on top of an overturned tub. This goddess\u2019s brother threw a flayed horse into a room containing her weavers, causing her to retreat into a cave in anger. This goddess, who was born when her father Izanagi washed his left eye, is worshiped at the Ise [ee-say] Shrine. The Emperor of Japan descended from, for ten points, what sun goddess of Shinto myth?", "answer": "<b> Amaterasu</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Radio host Alan Berg was murdered by a group advocating this belief known as the Order. Executions occur during the \u201cDay of the Rope\u201d in a book that furthers this belief, written by William Luther Pierce; that book is<em> The Turner Diaries</em>, pages of which were found in the car of Timothy McVeigh upon his arrest. The website<em> Stormfront</em> was founded by a former Grand Wizard of the Ku Klux Klan to promote, for ten points, what racial ideology promoted by groups like Aryan Nations?", "answer": "<b> white supremacism</b> (accept<b> white nationalism</b>; accept word forms; prompt on racism)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A former leader of this party was defeated in a 2017 election by Colin Clark. The 79 Group was a left wing faction of this party, whose supporters are divided into gradualist and fundamentalist wings. Winnie Ewing won the Hamilton riding in a 1967 by-election, this party\u2019s second-ever seat in Parliament. Nicola Sturgeon became the leader of this party after Alex Salmond resigned due to the failure of a 2014 independence referendum. For ten points, name this third largest political party in the British House of Commons, a prominent advocate for the independence of Scotland.", "answer": "<b> S</b>cottish<b> N</b>ational<b> P</b>arty", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "A commander from this state lost his right arm at the Battle of Fair Oaks and commanded the XI Corps [\u201celeventh core\u201d], who were decisively outflanked at the Battle of Chancellorsville. Union general O.O. Howard hailed from this state, as did the Vice President during much of the Civil War, Hannibal Hamlin. Joshua Chamberlain commanded this state\u2019s 20th Volunteer Regiment, which defended Little Round Top during the Battle of Gettysburg. For ten points, name this state where regiments were mustered near Portland.", "answer": "<b> Maine</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This work and a work accusing Samuel Chase of using insider knowledge to corner the flour market were published under the same name.<em> The New York Packet</em> published a section of this work that argues for paying the President an ample salary, thereby avoiding the temptation for corruption. Another section of this work claims that a Bill of Rights would be dangerous and unnecessary; that section is the 84th entry in this work. For ten points, name this series of essays that promote and defend the U.S. Constitution, written by Hamilton, Jay, and Madison.", "answer": "The<b> Federalist</b> Papers BONUS:<em> The Federalist Papers</em> were written by Jay, Hamilton, and Madison under this pseudonym. ANSWER:<b> Publius</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Winston Churchill criticized this man\u2019s government for \u201c[frolicing] [...] to their heart\u2019s content\u201d with the Germans and Japanese shortly after this man controversially offered formal condolences to the German embassy after the death of Hitler. This politician remarked \u201cthey are our people, and their sorrows are our sorrows\u201d after a neighboring country was attacked in the Belfast Blitz. Fianna Fail [fe-enna foil] was founded by, for ten points, what politician, the first Taoiseach [tee-shuh] of Ireland?", "answer": "Eamon de<b> Valera</b> (or Edward de<b> Valera</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In a Raphael portrait, one of these leaders appears lost in thought with a long white beard. A series of paintings showing these leaders with disfigured faces was created by Francis Bacon. A portrait of Felice, the illegitimate daughter of one of these leaders, appears in the Apostolic Palace. Diego Vel\u00b4azquez painted one of these men from the Pamphili family wearing glasses, Innocent X. For ten points, name these prominent patrons and subjects of art who head the Catholic Church.", "answer": "<b> Pope</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The local name of this discovery is \u201cDinkinesh,\u201d which translates to \u201cYou are marvelous\u201d in Amharic. Twenty years after this discovery was made, it was improved upon by Ardi, also found in the Awash River valley. A valgus knee and aspects of a conical rib cage were found as part of this discovery, indicating a plant-based diet and upright walking motion. This discovery consists of a few hundred fragments of bone, roughly 40 percent of a female Australopithecus skeleton. For ten points, name this collection of hominid fossils discovered in Ethiopia in 1974, named for the Beatles song playing in the excavators\u2019 camp.", "answer": "<b> Lucy</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Anthropology"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A ruler in this modern-day nation sided with Naples in the Treaty of Gaeta and formed the League of Lezh\u00a8e. Ismail Qemali [ish-mail kem-ah-lee] helped this nation gain independence at the Assembly of Vlor\u00a8e [v\u2019lor-uh]. In the 15th century, a historical region that became this nation fought off the Ottomans with the help of Skanderbeg. For ten points, name this Balkan nation that Enver Hoxha [hoh-cha] governed from its capital, Tirana.", "answer": "<b> Albania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In this country in 2016, referee C\u00b4esar Flores was shot and killed on the pitch by a player he\u2019d sent off. A soccer club in this country plays home games in the<em> La Bombonera</em>; that team is the Boca Juniors. During a heated game in the 1986 World Cup, a midfielder who played for this country scored the \u201cHand of God\u201d goal, shortly followed by the \u201cGoal of the Century.\u201d For ten points, name this country that lost the most recent World Cup Final to Germany and whose current roster includes Lionel Messi.", "answer": "<b> Argentina</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>Opponents of this man argued that his politics had been influenced by his affair with Jean Tatlock. This man, whose loyalty was questioned by the Borden Letter, was approached by a literature professor with (+) Soviet ties in the Chevalier Incident. This man\u2019s Q-Clearance was revoked just one day before it was to expire as the result of a (*)</b> 1954 security hearing. Accusations of communist sympathies tarnished the reputation of, for ten points, what scientist who directed the Los Alamos Laboratory as part of the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "J. Robert<b> Oppenheimer</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man stated \u201cGold is a relic of Julius Caesar, and interest is an invention of Satan\u201dwhile advocating for monetary reform. After the death of his wife, this man moved to West</b> <b>Orange where he built the Glenmont estate. This man founded a (+)</b> <b>film studio on the</b> <b>back of his kinetograph, which allowed him to make</b><em><b> The Great Train Robbery</b></em><b>. George (*) </b>Westinghouse feuded with this man, who participated in the \u201cWar of the Currents\u201d against his former employee, Nikola Tesla. Menlo Park was the home of, for ten points, what inventor commonly attributed with creating the light bulb?", "answer": "Thomas<b> Edison</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>The priest Francisco Romero demanded that people produce this commodity as penance. This commodity is cultivated in a namesake \u201ctriangle\u201d in the Paisa region. This commodity was produced in the Paraiba Valley in a boom starting in the 1890s, where it was shipped</b> <b>from (+)</b> <b>Santos. This commodity\u2019s production in the province of Sao Paulo, as opposed</b> <b>Santos. This commodity\u2019s production in the province of Sao Paulo, as opposed</b> <b>to Minas Gerais\u2019 [mee-nas zhe-RISE] production of (*)</b> <b>to Minas Gerais\u2019 [mee-nas zhe-RISE] production of (*)</b> dairy, provides the nickname of this commodity \u201cwith milk\u201d to a period of Brazilian history. For ten points, name this caffeinated beverage.", "answer": "<b> coffee</b> (accept<b> coffee</b> beans and other related answers)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>After one of these specific events, Mary Peckham became concerned after her neighbor\u2019s door was found to be locked. Reverend George Kelly was a suspect in one of these events at Villisca, Iowa. One of these incidents in New Orleans involved a letter that claimed</b> <b>if jazz music were played, (+)</b> <b>lives would be spared. One of these events was followed</b> <b>by testimony from the maid Bridget Sullivan in New Bedford, Massachusetts. U.S. Army officers Arthur Bonifas and Mark Barrett were the victims in another of these events that motivated Operation (*)</b> Paul Bunyan. Lizzie Borden was implicated in, for ten points, what type of event in which she \u201cgave her father forty-one\u201d whacks?", "answer": "<b> axe murder</b>s (accept descriptive answer of<b> killing</b> people with an<b> axe</b>; prompt on partial answers, like murder)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}